Rik L.E.M. Ubaghs

% rlemubaghs.com ♠ https://github.com/rlemubaghs ♠ Zurich, Switzerland wbaghs@aragolabs.com ♣ +31 6 51 45 01 60

Bio

I am a neural engineer specialized in neurotechnology. My areas of expertise are biomedical imaging, medical technology, brain-machine interfaces, and data analysis.

In my work, I am mostly interest in bridging the gab between experimental (neuro)technology and practical applications in the medical domain.

Education

ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland

July 2017 - May 2023

Ph.D. Neurotechnology

University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, the Netherlands

Sept 2014 - June 2016

Research Master Brain and Cognitive Sciences, Cum Laude

Maastricht University, Maastricht, the Netherlands Bachelor Psychology and Neuroscience, Cum Laude Sept 2011 - June 2014

Skills

Languages: Dutch (Native), English (Fluent), German (Basic)

Programming: Python, Matlab, Rust, R, SQL

Skills: Data Science, Biomedical Imaging, Microscopy, Mechanical design

Research Positions

AragoLabs (@Inst. of Neuroinformatics, ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland)

June 2023 - Current

Co-founder

Development of a miniaturized microscope for tumor visualization and classification during neurosurgery.

Inst. of Neuroinformatics, ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland

July 2017 - June 2023

Ph.D. Candidate

- Development of a MRI compatible florescence microscope (full-cycle product design).
- Design of a paradigm to combine microscopy and MR imaging methods in awake rodents.
- Design of data pipelines for multi-modal data analysis.

Center for Neuroengineering, Duke University, Durham, USA

Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Visitina Scientist

- Development of hybrid brain decoding methods in Non-human Primates.

Swammerdam Institute for Life Sciences, Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Aug 2015 – Dec 2015

- Internship
- Experimental design for sensory integration in rodents.
- Design of data analysis methods for high dimensional data.

Spinoza Center for Neuroimaging, Amsterdam, The Netherlands Junior Research Scientist

Nov 2014 - Dec 2015

- MR operator.
- Design and supervision of several large research projects.

Industry Positions

Agora Technology, Maastricht, The Netherlands

Nov 2016 - Feb 2018

Founder

- Built data solutions that aimed to streamline/automate the workflow within medical facilities, especially focussing on surgical equipment.
- Focused on logistics, and the creation, maintenance, and analysis of large-scale medical equipment databases using ML/DL.
- Clients included Maastricht University Medical Center and Medtronic.

Extracurricular Positions

Natural Movements, The Netherlands

March 2007 - May 2012

Co-Founder

- Natural Movements is a non-profit organization that aims to engage underprivileged youth in the local community through behavioral coaching and physical education.
- We worked together with social service organisations to provide youth with any additional support they required.

Publications

Research Papers:

- Simultaneous single-cell calcium imaging of neuronal population activity and brain-wide BOLD fMRI Ubaghs, R.L.E.M., Boehringer, R., Marks, M., Hesse, H.K., Yanik, M.F., Zerbi, V., Grewe, B.F., bioRxiv 2023.11.14.566368; doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.11.14.566368

Conference Abstracts:

- Ubaghs, R.L.E.M., Böhringer, R., Marks, M., Yanik, M.F. and Grewe, B.F., The Effect of Somatostatin+ Interneurons on the Negative BOLD Response. Proc. Intl. Soc. Mag. Reson. Med. 29 (2021)
- Ubaghs, R.L.E.M., Dermutz, H., Böhringer, R., Marks, M., Yanik, M.F. and Grewe, B.F., Shaping the BOLD signal through Excitatory and Inhibitory Interaction. Proc. Intl. Soc. Mag. Reson. Med. 28 (2020)

Honors

Committees:

Educational Committee, IIS, University of Amsterdam	Sept 2014 - June 2015
Vice-President Student Council, FPN, Maastricht University	Sept 2012 - June 2013
Program Committee, FPN, Maastricht University	Sept 2012 - June 2013

Grants:

Hendrik Muller Memorial Foundation	2016
Bekker - La Bastide Memorial Foundation	2015
Vrijvrouwe van Renswoude Foundation	2015